<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-03T16:14:15-05:00</updated><id>http://www.petergee.dev/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Peter Gee</title><subtitle>Software Engineer</subtitle><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><entry><title type="html">Interview Impressions: Infinite Campus</title><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/04/09/interview-impressions-infinite-campus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interview Impressions: Infinite Campus" /><published>2019-04-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.petergee.dev/2019/04/09/interview-impressions-infinite-campus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/04/09/interview-impressions-infinite-campus/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infinitecampus.com/&quot;&gt;Infinite Campus&lt;/a&gt; is the only company where I’ve interviewed that had no phone or online screening step. We went straight to an onsite interview. When the time came, one of my interviewers arrived 15 minutes late, and the other arrived 25 minutes late. They pulled up my resume on a phone and then squinted as they tried read its contents. I was caught off guard by the format of the interview: 30 minutes with the first 2 interviewers and then 30 minutes with a solo interviewer. I had been told I would only be interviewing with the hiring manager. When I casually mentioned how I hadn’t expected this, my interviewer acted offended, as though I had no right to question how they do things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t keep a list of questions, but I noted 2 that I wanted to be more prepared for in the future. One interviewer asked, “What do you want to get out of working here besides real world experience?” This shouldn’t be a difficult question, but real world experience was by far the biggest thing I wanted to get out of working an internship, and I hadn’t thought about alternative answers. Another asked, “What are the differences between C++ and Java at the compiler level?” I answered by explaining general differences between the 2 languages, but I should have specifically addressed differences in how they are compiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With some of the things mentioned above in mind, Infinite Campus’s interviewing process left me feeling underwhelmed. I suspect they sensed my lack of enthusiasm as well. They were already at the bottom of my list due to the distant location from my home, and the interview sealed the deal. As a disclaimer, I’d like to point out that this was just one experience with just a few people. I have nothing negative to say about the company as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">Infinite Campus is the only company where I’ve interviewed that had no phone or online screening step. We went straight to an onsite interview. When the time came, one of my interviewers arrived 15 minutes late, and the other arrived 25 minutes late. They pulled up my resume on a phone and then squinted as they tried read its contents. I was caught off guard by the format of the interview: 30 minutes with the first 2 interviewers and then 30 minutes with a solo interviewer. I had been told I would only be interviewing with the hiring manager. When I casually mentioned how I hadn’t expected this, my interviewer acted offended, as though I had no right to question how they do things.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.petergee.dev/public/images/interview-impressions-infinite-campus-logo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Interview Impressions: NextEra Energy</title><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/04/02/interview-impressions-nextera-energy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interview Impressions: NextEra Energy" /><published>2019-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.petergee.dev/2019/04/02/interview-impressions-nextera-energy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/04/02/interview-impressions-nextera-energy/">&lt;p&gt;Of everywhere I’ve interviewed, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nexteraenergy.com/&quot;&gt;NextEra Energy&lt;/a&gt; had the shortest interview process. It began with a request for an online interview through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hirevue.com/&quot;&gt;HireVue&lt;/a&gt;. This included 3 prelimary typed questions about my GPA, major, and graduation date. Following these I was asked 4 questions in which my answers would be 2-minute video recordings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions asked included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is your cumulative GPA?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is your major?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is your intended graduation date?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Describe yourself using five words.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What most interests you about working this job?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me about a time when you went above and beyond requirements either in a course or on a job.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are you main career goals/interests? What is the biggest factor in keeping you at NextEra after an internship?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was mostly straight forward, although it is a bit off-putting to speak to a webcam instead of an interviewer if you’re not used to it. A month later I was contacted for a “30 minute phone interview with the Software Engineering team.” This second interview ended up lasting only 16 minutes. Instead of alternating between questions and answers, my interviewer asked for the first 5 questions all at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions asked included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduce yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk about your coursework.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are your career goals?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Summarize the projects on your resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take 1 or 2 projects and go into detail about implementation, your development environment, what kind of approach you took, your framework, who you worked with, how big the team was, and how you organized your work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you have experience with Agile, Scrum, Git, GitHub, and version control?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What development environment are you most comfortable with: Linux, Mac, Windows?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are you looking for in an internship?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is Java your strongest language?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this interview I also learned I would be working with &lt;a href=&quot;http://windlogics.com/&quot;&gt;WindLogics&lt;/a&gt;, a subsidiary of NextEra Energy. They have a team of 100 people, with 60 in Minnesota and 40 in Florida. They use Java, specifically the &lt;a href=&quot;https://spring.io/&quot;&gt;Spring Framework&lt;/a&gt;, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/&quot;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt;. For UI they use &lt;a href=&quot;https://angularjs.org/&quot;&gt;Angular&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://vuejs.org/&quot;&gt;Vue&lt;/a&gt;. They do 2 week sprints.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">Of everywhere I’ve interviewed, NextEra Energy had the shortest interview process. It began with a request for an online interview through HireVue. This included 3 prelimary typed questions about my GPA, major, and graduation date. Following these I was asked 4 questions in which my answers would be 2-minute video recordings.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.petergee.dev/public/images/interview-impressions-nextera-energy-logo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Interview Impressions: Invenshure</title><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/26/interview-impressions-invenshure/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interview Impressions: Invenshure" /><published>2019-03-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/26/interview-impressions-invenshure</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/26/interview-impressions-invenshure/">&lt;p&gt;I applied at &lt;a href=&quot;https://invenshure.com/&quot;&gt;Invenshure&lt;/a&gt; through &lt;a href=&quot;https://scitechmn.org/&quot;&gt;SciTechsperience&lt;/a&gt;. As a biotech incubator, Invenshure’s goal is to “build companies that change the world by turning hard problems into thriving businesses.” I got a phone interview scheduled with an embedded systems engineer who seemed to also be in charge of hiring interns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions asked included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you know about Invenshure?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s your proudest project? Tell me about it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me more about your &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/currency/&quot;&gt;Market Maker Bot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What area of software development are you most interested in?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Between web development and scientific development, which is your preference?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It lasted 18 minutes. My interviewer described how interns are assigned to one of Invenshure’s portfolio companies, although they still technically work for Invenshure. Although several things stood out to me about Invenshure, one that made them a top choice for me was simply the fact that they were open to interns working part time in the spring. That means I’d be able to potentially work another internship over the summer, giving me even more experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interviewer followed up instantly to ask for times that would work for an onsite interview. He said I’d be interviewing with 3-4 people including a current intern, that there would be a small technical portion, and that I should bring something from my portfolio to show such as &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/beginnings/&quot;&gt;Beginnings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the interview was scheduled for an hour, I arrived 15 minutes early and ended up leaving 15 minutes late. It began with a tour, and after that was an interview with 4 employees: an embedded systems engineer (my first interviewer), a chief software architect, a software engineer, and a software engineer intern. It was incredibly conversational and unscripted. They wanted to see Beginnings, so the majority of the time involved showing them the ins and outs of the game from my laptop projected onto a TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a half hour or so they left with the exception of the software engineer. He gave me a software test with 3 portions which would be completed with pseudocode on a whiteboard:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Given a string, write a function to determine whether it’s a palindrome&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Given an array of 1s and 0s, determine the number of groups of consecutive 1s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Given a matrix of 1s and 0s, determine the number of islands (with an “island” defined as being separated by at least one 0 in both dimensions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I aced the first two, and I started on an answer to the third but admitted I’d need more time to come up with a sufficient solution. He gave me some credit for recognizing the edge case where my initial algorithm would fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the interviews I learned they were looking for 4-5 interns, most of whom would come in the summer. Interns are placed in different portfolio companies based on their skillset. I was told I was a “very impressive” candidate and that I could potentially even choose which portfolio company I’d like to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks later I got an offer to start in the spring, as I had hoped. &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/03/16/interview-impressions-prep-network/&quot;&gt;Prep Network&lt;/a&gt; had been my only other possibility for a spring internship. I accepted Invenshure’s offer and am working there to this day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">I applied at Invenshure through SciTechsperience. As a biotech incubator, Invenshure’s goal is to “build companies that change the world by turning hard problems into thriving businesses.” I got a phone interview scheduled with an embedded systems engineer who seemed to also be in charge of hiring interns.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.petergee.dev/public/images/interview-impressions-invenshure-logo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Interview Impressions: U.S. Bank</title><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/19/interview-impressions-us-bank/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interview Impressions: U.S. Bank" /><published>2019-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/19/interview-impressions-us-bank</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/19/interview-impressions-us-bank/">&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine who had interviewed at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usbank.com/&quot;&gt;U.S. Bank&lt;/a&gt; the year before didn’t like what he saw. He had gotten an offer from them, but his impression was that they used outdated technology, outsourced a lot of development to India, and didn’t pay well compared to other internships. Needless to say, my first impression of U.S. Bank’s program wasn’t good. I had already decided not to turn down any interviews, though, so I accepted when they contacted me for a phone interview with a campus relations manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions asked included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did you choose this program?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give an example of a team project that did not go as expected.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me a time when you explained the technical details of a project and what the end result was.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When did you have a difficult conversation and how did you prepare for it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give an example of when you had to do something you had never done before.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give an example of using a technical tool or language to enhance a project.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give an example of feedback you got and how you adjusted based on it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was a potentially significant problem that came up and what steps did you take to resolve it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interview lasted 19 minutes. I learned it would be a 10-week internship starting on June 3. Each intern is assigned a mentor from a different department. My interviewer told me they would finish phone interviews that week, present candidates to HR the following week, and get back to me about a 30-minute interview in two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, they contacted me a couple of weeks later about an onsite interview. The day of the interview, they emailed me to let me know that the interview was switched to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webex.com/&quot;&gt;WebEx&lt;/a&gt; instead of being onsite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions asked included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why do you want to work here?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me about &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/beginnings/&quot;&gt;Beginnings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s an interesting technology problem you solved?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What experience do you have with SQL?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me about &lt;a href=&quot;https://unwsp.edu/&quot;&gt;Northwestern’s&lt;/a&gt; competition that you won.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What interests you about information security?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What change management do you use for Beginnings?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interviewer this time around was a developer. He spent more time talking about the internship program than asking me questions. He said they were recruiting for an agile team with 6 members. Their focus is Java and SQL, and they work with a database containing 400 tables. They dress business casual and are becoming less formal over time. They used to have 1-2 hour meetings but now do 15-20 minute daily stand ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed up with them a couple weeks later, and they said they hadn’t made a decision yet. They ended up leaving me a message saying they’d chosen another candidate. A few weeks after that they told me a new position had opened up, and they wanted to know if I was still interested. I wasn’t, as I had already received offers from several companies where I’d rather work.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">A friend of mine who had interviewed at U.S. Bank the year before didn’t like what he saw. He had gotten an offer from them, but his impression was that they used outdated technology, outsourced a lot of development to India, and didn’t pay well compared to other internships. Needless to say, my first impression of U.S. Bank’s program wasn’t good. I had already decided not to turn down any interviews, though, so I accepted when they contacted me for a phone interview with a campus relations manager.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.petergee.dev/public/images/interview-impressions-us-bank-logo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Interview Impressions: Prep Network</title><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/16/interview-impressions-prep-network/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interview Impressions: Prep Network" /><published>2019-03-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/16/interview-impressions-prep-network</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/16/interview-impressions-prep-network/">&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prepnetwork.com/&quot;&gt;Prep Network&lt;/a&gt; when its CEO contacted me via my enrollment in &lt;a href=&quot;https://scitechmn.org/&quot;&gt;SciTechsperience&lt;/a&gt;. Prep Network’s goal is “to be the country’s most comprehensive resource for evaluation and recruitment in high school athletics.” Having only 11 full time employees, it’s the smallest company where I’ve interviewed. We scheduled a phone interview which lasted 23 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions asked included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me about yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have you had a chance to research Prep Network? What do you know about us?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did you decide to apply here? What appeals to you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did you major in Computer Science?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What area of Computer Science do you focus on? Front end, back end, full stack?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What else are you passionate about?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you manage work/life balance (or academic/life balance)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are your expectations for the internship?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are your favorite programming languages?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you have PHP experience?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; experience?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; experience?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you have experience with APIs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It became clear they were looking for a full stack developer with a background in JavaScript and PHP. It was also evident that the interviewer himself—being a CEO—didn’t have a developer background. That explained why his questions were so general and why he asked a question as vague as, “Do you have experience with APIs?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was honest with him. I had used PHP, WordPress, and Bootstrap at various times in my life, but I wasn’t exactly confident with any of them. I enjoy JavaScript, but PHP is my least favorite language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I asked about the work environment, he said they generally work 9 to 5 but have flexible hours and the potential to work remotely. They use &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com/&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; 20 hours a day, but “obviously that’s not a job requirement.” Their 2 full time developers have a long term project as well as small projects throughout the week. They have weekly development meetings and set quarterly objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He mentioned that he had already interviewed 10 other candidates, but only 3 will be invited to an on-site interview in a few weeks. These would be determined based on a 1-2 hour online coding test. He never ended up sending me the coding test. After a few weeks he let me know they had decided on another candidate.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">I was introduced to Prep Network when its CEO contacted me via my enrollment in SciTechsperience. Prep Network’s goal is “to be the country’s most comprehensive resource for evaluation and recruitment in high school athletics.” Having only 11 full time employees, it’s the smallest company where I’ve interviewed. We scheduled a phone interview which lasted 23 minutes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.petergee.dev/public/images/interview-impressions-prep-network-logo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Interview Impressions: RevTrak</title><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/14/interview-impressions-revtrak/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interview Impressions: RevTrak" /><published>2019-03-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/14/interview-impressions-revtrak</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/14/interview-impressions-revtrak/">&lt;p&gt;Over the course of my summer 2018 internship search I applied to around 10 companies. The only company I ended up interviewing with was the only one that reached out to me first: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.revtrak.com/&quot;&gt;RevTrak&lt;/a&gt;, a K-12 payment processing company. They most likely contacted me due to my connections with the human resources assistant and other employees through church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My roommate had worked there the previous summer and gave high praise of the work environment. I thus had a good first impression of the company, although this was diminished somewhat when it took them a couple months to respond to my application. Finally a senior technical lead contacted me for a phone interview that lasted 20 minutes. Looking back, it went surprisngly well for my first phone interview ever, although the first question did catch me off guard (which was most likely the intention).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions asked included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where do you see yourself in 20 years?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where do you see yourself in 5 years?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where do you see yourself in 1 year?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What kind of tasks are you best at?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What kind of tasks do you most enjoy?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What kind of tasks do you least enjoy?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Could you give me a 5 minute rundown of &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/beginnings/&quot;&gt;Beginnings&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are some things you’ve heard about RevTrak?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s your decision making timeline?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s your most important factor in making a decision?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On a scale of 1-10, how likely would you be to return to RevTrak as an employee later?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you think this job is a good fit for you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interviewer told me they do 2-week &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_(software_development)&quot;&gt;Scrum&lt;/a&gt; sprints with a company-wide stand up at 9 AM each day followed by team stand ups afterwards. Some tools they use are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira&quot;&gt;Jira&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/tfs/&quot;&gt;Microsoft TFS&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://products.office.com/en-us/microsoft-teams/group-chat-software&quot;&gt;Microsoft Teams&lt;/a&gt;. They would contact me for a 1.5-3 hour interview to meet the team and have a coding test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The onsite interview had 3 parts. The first involved 2 interviewers, one of whom was the phone interviewer. They generally asked similar questions to the phone interview, although one that stood out was, “Name 3 things you are not.” They also asked me to write pseudocode on a whiteboard with my solution to a problem that I had seen in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crackingthecodinginterview.com/&quot;&gt;Cracking the Coding Interview&lt;/a&gt; (interview question 1.2 in the 6th edition): “Given two strings, write a method to decide if one is a permutation of the other.” They were expecting &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/careercup/CtCI-6th-Edition/blob/master/Java/Ch%2001.%20Arrays%20and%20Strings/Q1_02_Check_Permutation/QuestionA.java&quot;&gt;solution A&lt;/a&gt;, but I gave them &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/careercup/CtCI-6th-Edition/blob/master/Java/Ch%2001.%20Arrays%20and%20Strings/Q1_02_Check_Permutation/QuestionB.java&quot;&gt;solution B&lt;/a&gt;. For context, solution A was more straightforward and debatably cleaner, while solution B had improved time complexity and thus better performance. Growing up as a game developer, my instinct is typically to make performance a priority. Since this interview, I’ve been learning that most developers focus much more on code cleanliness than code efficiency. I don’t blame them; performance just isn’t as important in business as it is in gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second interview had me talking casually with 3 developers who I’d be working with. I got the feeling they were testing how well I’d fit in with their team’s culture. They clearly had less of an agenda compared to the other interviewers. They were just developers. Interviewing wasn’t a normal part of their jobs. The focus also turned to my resume. We talked about past projects, teams, classes, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to this point I had been feeling good. It was the third and final interview that made me sweat. A stoic senior developer had me writing code on paper for an hour or so on a strange coding test (the earlier test was a “warm up”) that required in-depth knowledge of Java that I wasn’t prepared for. I had made it clear to the earlier interviewers that I was rusty with my Java, and they assured me I’d be fine. That wasn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t end up getting the job, but what I learned from RevTrak set me up well for my interviews the following year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">Over the course of my summer 2018 internship search I applied to around 10 companies. The only company I ended up interviewing with was the only one that reached out to me first: RevTrak, a K-12 payment processing company. They most likely contacted me due to my connections with the human resources assistant and other employees through church.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.petergee.dev/public/images/interview-impressions-revtrak-logo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Interview Impressions: Intro</title><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/12/interview-impressions-intro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interview Impressions: Intro" /><published>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/12/interview-impressions-intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/03/12/interview-impressions-intro/">&lt;p&gt;I haven’t uploaded anything lately, so this week I’ll be writing 3 posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular post marks the start of a series I’m calling &lt;em&gt;Interview Impressions&lt;/em&gt;. This will be a set of around 10 posts in which I’ll summarize my interactions with and impressions of companies where I interviewed. With the exception of RevTrak, where I interviewed over a year ago, the interviews took place between late November 2018 and early January 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why write this series?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My search for a summer 2018 internship was halfhearted. There were several other things I wanted to do with my summer, and although I had some job experience, I really didn’t have any job &lt;em&gt;search&lt;/em&gt; experience. I look back on that period thankful for all the lessons I learned that allowed me to be much more successful the second time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially the most daunting part of the job search process was interviewing. I didn’t know what to expect. If I would have had access to a series of posts that explained how various companies conducted their software developer interviews, I would have felt much more prepared. It would have given me concrete context instead of being left with vague preconceptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, I hope this series helps anyone who finds themselves in a similar place of not knowing what to expect. Of course, it will also serve as a record of history that I’ll be able to look back on years from now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">I haven’t uploaded anything lately, so this week I’ll be writing 3 posts. This particular post marks the start of a series I’m calling Interview Impressions. This will be a set of around 10 posts in which I’ll summarize my interactions with and impressions of companies where I interviewed. With the exception of RevTrak, where I interviewed over a year ago, the interviews took place between late November 2018 and early January 2019. So why write this series?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Basic Microtransaction Categories</title><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/02/19/microtransaction-categories/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basic Microtransaction Categories" /><published>2019-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://www.petergee.dev/2019/02/19/microtransaction-categories</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/02/19/microtransaction-categories/">&lt;p&gt;Monetization is one of the most controversial topics in gaming today. Should a game have a single upfront cost? Should it be free-to-play? What about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freemium&quot;&gt;freemium&lt;/a&gt;? Are loot boxes ethical? What should we sell, and what should be off limits? Should a game’s monetization scheme depend on its genre?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These questions are particularly relevant for competitive online games with plenty of interaction between players. Since &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/beginnings/&quot;&gt;Beginnings&lt;/a&gt; falls under that description this is a topic I’ve put a lot of thought into. In our case we originally had no intentions of selling anything because we had no idea the game would become popular. Since then we’ve adopted a freemium model. We offer the vast majority of the game for free, but certain additional features or customizations are for sale. It seems to me that there are 4 basic categories that these kinds of microtransactions can be split into: power, mechanic, convenience, and cosmetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;power&quot;&gt;Power&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example: Buy this and double your max health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Power transactions are selling things like better stats, better equipment, and so on. Power microtransactions usually manifest themselves as the “pay to win” model that most gamers rightfully despise. However, I believe there are rare cases where this kind of monetization is acceptable. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collectible_card_game&quot;&gt;Collectible card games&lt;/a&gt; (CCG) are one such exception. CCGs are a breed of their own. Because much of a CCG’s gameplay actually takes place when building a deck rather than playing a deck, interesting questions come up such as, “should I buy 10 decent cards or 1 rare card?” or “how can I build the best deck for under $100?” Selling cards of varying power thus enhances the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/images/microtransaction-categories-magic.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to reiterate that selling power is almost always a terrible idea. Doing so makes your players feel cheated, and it makes you look greedy. We will never sell power microtransactions in Beginnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mechanic&quot;&gt;Mechanic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example: Buy this and craft hot air balloons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mechanic microtransactions enable players to do something mechanically that they wouldn’t have been able to otherwise. They’re safer than power microtransactions, but they still need to be handled with care. These make sense for some but certainly not all games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/images/microtransaction-categories-balloon.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Beginnings, we plan to sell unique recipes such as a hot air balloon and a hang glider. While these do give players a boost, we aren’t boosting something black and white. We’re selling something more subjective than a numeric power boost. We’re just letting them do something cool. Hovering in a balloon means you’re vulnerable to fire arrows, and you’ll starve or run out of fuel if you stay in the air too long. We’re putting these limitations in place to prevent a mechanic microtransaction from becoming a power microtransaction. Admittedly the line between the two is sometimes blurry, and this is something I’m still figuring out for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;convenience&quot;&gt;Convenience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example: Buy this and level up faster&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convenience microtransactions are most often the sale of time. That is, a game might allow players to level up faster once they pay up. Maybe there’s a part of the game that can be unlocked after completing a certain number of levels, but buying a convenience microtransaction allows them to skip those levels and get to the good stuff right away. &lt;a href=&quot;https://supercell.com/en/games/clashofclans/&quot;&gt;Clash of Clans&lt;/a&gt; is one of the clearest examples of this type of monetization. The game lets you speed up processes that would otherwise take hours. You can wait for your resources to grow, or you can just pay and get resources instantly. It’s money in exchange for time. There are also other kinds of convenience microtransactions such as selling storage space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/images/microtransaction-categories-clash.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convenience microtransactions are often a safe option. Players feel much better about microtransactions if they know that anything they can buy can also be earned by just playing for a while longer. However, it’s important to strike a balance. If convenience items are too cheap, players won’t want to spend time playing your game because you’ve shown that their time isn’t valuable. If convenience items are too expensive, you’re losing out on players who just want a good time within their budget. In Beginnings we plan to sell convenience items such as starterpacks that let you start a server with a few items. Like other kinds of convenience microtransactions, starterpacks are ultimately about saving time because they mean you don’t have to go around and gather basic tools every time you join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cosmetic&quot;&gt;Cosmetic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example: Buy this and make your shield look cool&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cosmetic microtransactions are the safest of all. Since they generally cannot be abused, nobody feels cheated. Games like &lt;a href=&quot;https://na.leagueoflegends.com/en/&quot;&gt;League of Legends&lt;/a&gt; sell skins that change the way your champion looks. These are perfect for highly competitive games (whereas power and mechanic microtransactions are not) because the balance of power is so delicate. If a player feels even slightly cheated in a MOBA, they’re going to find another MOBA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/images/microtransaction-categories-league.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Beginnings we are definitely going to take sell cosmetic items. One of the first will be shield variations; your shield can look Nordic, Roman, or Elven if you pay the price. We also plan on selling recipe variations that let you craft normal objects such as furniture out of unique materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power microtransactions&lt;/strong&gt; are rarely a good idea. Try to avoid them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mechanic microtransactions&lt;/strong&gt; work well for some games but not others. Avoid disguising a power upgrade as a mechanic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convenience microtransactions&lt;/strong&gt; are fairly safe to sell, but you need to be careful with pricing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosmetic microtransactions&lt;/strong&gt; are the safest of all. There’s no reason not to sell them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">Monetization is one of the most controversial topics in gaming today. Should a game have a single upfront cost? Should it be free-to-play? What about freemium? Are loot boxes ethical? What should we sell, and what should be off limits? Should a game’s monetization scheme depend on its genre? These questions are particularly relevant for competitive online games with plenty of interaction between players. Since Beginnings falls under that description this is a topic I’ve put a lot of thought into. In our case we originally had no intentions of selling anything because we had no idea the game would become popular. Since then we’ve adopted a freemium model. We offer the vast majority of the game for free, but certain additional features or customizations are for sale. It seems to me that there are 4 basic categories that these kinds of microtransactions can be split into: power, mechanic, convenience, and cosmetic.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.petergee.dev/public/images/microtransaction-categories-clash.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">You Copied Minecraft!</title><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/02/12/copied-minecraft/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Copied Minecraft!" /><published>2019-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://www.petergee.dev/2019/02/12/copied-minecraft</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/02/12/copied-minecraft/">&lt;p&gt;A common remark I hear when someone first plays Beginnings is that we copied Minecraft. It’s true there are similarities; I even describe our game as being similar to Minecraft. Despite this, similarity does not imply copying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-had-survival-gameplay-first&quot;&gt;We had survival gameplay first.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/01/22/history-beginnings/&quot;&gt;As discussed previously&lt;/a&gt;, Beginnings is just one part of a family of games I call The Survival Series. The first of these, Survival 101, was released in June 2009. Minecraft didn’t release its &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraft.gamepedia.com/Survival_Test&quot;&gt;first survival version&lt;/a&gt; until September 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, Survival 101 included many features that are today associated with Minecraft before Minecraft itself did. For everything we’ve kept the same since 101, we clearly didn’t copy Minecraft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-core-gameplay-differences&quot;&gt;There are core gameplay differences.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if The Survival Series had been created after Minecraft added a survival mode, it would still not be fair to claim that Beginnings is a Minecraft clone. The most important reason for this is that playing the two games feels fundamentally different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraft.gamepedia.com/Minecraft_Wiki&quot;&gt;According to the Minecraft Wiki&lt;/a&gt;, Minecraft is a “sandbox construction game.” It’s about being able to gather resources (“mine”) and create anything from those resources (“craft”). It is not originally a survival game. Stripped to its core, it’s about shaping the world around you, not about surviving. Most of the survival in Minecraft becomes trivial anyway once you acquire sufficient resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, there are no game modes in Beginnings. There is only survival. Surviving never becomes trivial because there will always be the threat of other players. There are also many permanent structures in Beginnings such as mountains and oceans. Compared to Minecraft, Beginnings has less emphasis on sandbox gameplay and more emphasis on survival gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So no, we didn’t copy Minecraft.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">A common remark I hear when someone first plays Beginnings is that we copied Minecraft. It’s true there are similarities; I even describe our game as being similar to Minecraft. Despite this, similarity does not imply copying.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.petergee.dev/public/images/copied-minecraft-logo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Senior Project Ideas</title><link href="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/02/05/senior-project-ideas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Senior Project Ideas" /><published>2019-02-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://www.petergee.dev/2019/02/05/senior-project-ideas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.petergee.dev/2019/02/05/senior-project-ideas/">&lt;p&gt;This semester I have two main focuses: my internship and my senior project. Last month I started an internship at &lt;a href=&quot;https://invenshure.com/&quot;&gt;Invenshure&lt;/a&gt; — more on that in a future post. This month I’m starting on my senior project. Although my advisor Dr. Zderad allows great flexibility in choosing a topic, the focus should be on actually creating something. Research is secondary for this particular project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally the first step is choosing a topic, and over the past couple months I’ve thought through a few ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3D Object Fitting Algorithm (C++)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bible Memory Mobile App (Java)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stock Market Prediction (Python)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beginnings 2 (Lua)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3d-object-fitting-algorithm-c&quot;&gt;3D Object Fitting Algorithm (C++)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/images/senior-project-ideas-protolabs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When interviewing at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protolabs.com/&quot;&gt;Protolabs&lt;/a&gt; I asked: “Do you have an idea of something I could work on in preparation for the internship?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interviewers gave several topics I could learn about: version control, Visual Studio, large codebases, geometry and linear algebra, and file I/O in C++. One that stuck out was the simple task of fitting a box around a 3D object at a low level. I decided this would work well as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product&quot;&gt;minimum viable product&lt;/a&gt;, and more features could be added over time: shapes more complex than a box, changes in orientation to allow for better fitting, and perhaps ultimately an algorithm that assigns a value to how well a given object fits into a given shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bible-memory-mobile-app-java&quot;&gt;Bible Memory Mobile App (Java)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/images/senior-project-ideas-bible.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://biblememory.com/&quot;&gt;The Bible Memory App&lt;/a&gt; to learn scripture. There’s a lot to like, but I can’t help but think I could do a better job. It lacks several features I consider crucial as well as some that would just be handy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Option to learn verse numbers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Option to memorize from the original Greek and Hebrew&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accurate progression: the app says a verse is “memorized” the first time you work on it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More than one way to memorize a verse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dark mode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stricter requirements: type first 2 letters, require the grammar, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In-app resources about scripture memory (articles, quotes, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better monetization (charging for versions of the Bible? &lt;em&gt;Really?&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sansforgetica.rmit/&quot;&gt;Sans Forgetica&lt;/a&gt; (because why not)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android notifications that &lt;em&gt;actually work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows, maybe there’s already an app out there that has these features. But the fact that one of the most popular options falls short of the mark tells me there’s an opportunity here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stock-market-prediction-python&quot;&gt;Stock Market Prediction (Python)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the craziest idea I’ve been considering is stock market prediction. Certainly many have tried, and I too would likely fail, but failure can be glorious if you learn something in the process. Data science is an area I’m interested in but haven’t yet dived into. Even my initial research shows &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/i-spent-20-minutes-trying-to-predict-the-stock-market-with-ai-these-are-my-results-59d48c7a388a&quot;&gt;someone achieving 54% accuracy in 20 minutes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve already written a &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/currency/&quot;&gt;profitable trading algorithm&lt;/a&gt;, but competition would be several orders of magnitude greater on the actual stock market. Of course I would start with a simulator to make trades if I ever got to that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stock market appeals to me because gathering data and judging success are both straight forward. This means I could focus on the algorithm itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/images/senior-project-ideas-stocks.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beginnings-2-lua&quot;&gt;Beginnings 2 (Lua)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While every idea here appeals to me, the one I am actually most excited about is finishing &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/beginnings/&quot;&gt;Beginnings 2&lt;/a&gt;. Although the game is nearly finished, even the remaining work is larger than a typical senior project. With that in mind, I asked my advisor whether this would be an option and he encouraged it. I’ve now decided that this will be my senior project, and I believe it’s the push I need to finally finish the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/images/senior-project-ideas-beginnings.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">This semester I have two main focuses: my internship and my senior project. Last month I started an internship at Invenshure — more on that in a future post. This month I’m starting on my senior project. Although my advisor Dr. Zderad allows great flexibility in choosing a topic, the focus should be on actually creating something. Research is secondary for this particular project. Naturally the first step is choosing a topic, and over the past couple months I’ve thought through a few ideas: 3D Object Fitting Algorithm (C++) Bible Memory Mobile App (Java) Stock Market Prediction (Python) Beginnings 2 (Lua)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.petergee.dev/public/images/senior-project-ideas-beginnings.jpg" /></entry></feed>