<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-04T13:37:11-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Peter Gee</title><subtitle>Software engineer studying computer science at &lt;a href=&quot;https://unwsp.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UNWSP&lt;/a&gt;</subtitle><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><entry><title type="html">Hello World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2018/01/01/hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2018/01/01/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2018/01/01/hello-world/">&lt;p&gt;Hi there! I’m Peter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote my first line of code when I was eight, and I’ve loved it ever since. Since then I’ve created games, desktop apps, databases, macros, websites, web crawlers, trading algorithms–whatever piques my curiosity, really. I’m fascinated by interesting problems, and I enjoy writing code to solve them. I’m currently majoring in computer science at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://unwsp.edu/&quot;&gt;University of Northwestern – St. Paul&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ll graduate later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this first post I’d like to get a few things out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-is-a-developer-blog&quot;&gt;This is a developer blog.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus is on technology, not on me. This is meant as a space for me to share my thoughts about relevant topics in computer science that interest me and that I believe may interest others. I will also write about projects I’m working on. This is intentionally broad because I don’t want to restrict myself to specific topics so early on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-have-several-reasons-for-writing-here&quot;&gt;I have several reasons for writing here.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To learn new things constantly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To master what I’m learning by teaching it to others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To keep a historical record of my thoughts and work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To benefit readers by adding something unique to the conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no intention of reaching a wide audience. Even if nobody reads what I write, my first three goals will be fulfilled. That is enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;posts-will-be-published-every-tuesday-at-minimum&quot;&gt;Posts will be published every Tuesday at minimum.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This schedule will help to keep myself accountable. It may change to become more or less frequent as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I’ll move beyond introduction and start discussing topics in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Gee</name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">Hi there! I’m Peter.</summary></entry></feed>